Morris Lapidus Papers
Morris Lapidus Papers
circa 1915-2010
Lapidus, Morris
24 linear ft.
Papers of the architect and designer, includes photographs and slides, a limited number of architectural drawings, correspondence and personal and professional writings.
150328
Biographical History
Morris Lapidus (1902-2001) was a Russian-born American architect and designer.
Morris Lapidus was born on November 25, 1902 in Odessa, Russia, the son of Estonian and Polish Jews. In 1903, his family immigrated to New York City. They lived in lower Manhattan before moving to Brooklyn, first to Williamsburg and during his high school years to East New York. Lapidus's design sensibility was shaped by his experience of life in New York's tenements and exposure to the spectacle of Coney Island. He graduated from the Boys High School in Bedford-Stuyvesant and enrolled in New York University, intending to purse a degree in drama. He hoped to become an actor but eventually turned his attention to scenic design. He transferred to Columbia University's School of Architecture during the 1920s. Lapidus was deeply interested by -- but received little instruction in -- the revolutionary modernism of European architects such as Le Corbusier, Mies van der Rohe and Eliel Saarinen. His first job (while he was still in school) was in the drafting room of Warren and Whetmore, a prominent New York architecture firm.
He received his bachelor's degree in Architecture from Columbia in 1927. He was hired first by the firm Block and Hess, developing the ornamentation for buildings, and then by the architect, Arthur Weiser. Lapidus's big break came when he began to work for Ross-Frankel, a firm that designed storefronts. He began to create distinctive, and very modern, storefronts, which used color and light to draw customers into the store. He also developed a number of characteristic forms known as "cheese holes," "woggles" and "bean poles," which he would continue to use throughout his career.
Lapidus worked for Ross-Frankel for 15 years, finally opening his own office during World War II. He continued to design store fronts until one of his clients introduced him to Ben Novak, who was building a hotel in Miami Beach called the Sans Souci. His work with Novak on the Sans Souci led to other commissions, and Lapidus quickly made a name for himself as the associate architect for a number of hotels in the area: the Nautilus, the DiLido, the Biltmore Terrace and the Algiers. His most famous individually-designed hotels were built during the 1950s, including the Fontainebleau and the Eden Roc. Lapidus used techniques learned in storefront and stage design to create dramatic public spaces that provided guests with a sense of adventure and escape.
In addition to hotels he worked on other public spaces, such as the 1960 redesign of Lincoln Road in Miami Beach, turning it into one of the nation's first pedestrian malls. He also built office buildings, private residences, and community and religious buildings, although they were a smaller percentage of his architectural output. Lapidus continued to enjoy a lucrative and international career in hotel design throughout the 1970s. He retired in 1983, at which time he destroyed most of his drawings.
Lapidus often found himself at odds with an architectural establishment that favored some version of Modernism. His reputation began to be resuscitated with An Architecture of Joy, a controversial exhibition of his work mounted by the Architectural League of New York in 1970. Beginning in 1994, he worked with architect, Deborah Desilets, who devoted herself to changing the critical perception of Lapidus's work. Both Lapidus and Desilets gave many lectures on his legacy, and together they designed furniture and a night club, Aura, at 613 Lincoln Road, Miami Beach, FL.
Lapidus married his wife, Beatrice Perlman, in 1929. The couple had two sons, Richard, a lawyer, and Alan who followed in his father's footsteps and became an architect. Morris Lapidus died at home after an accidental fall, on January 18, 2001 at the age of 98.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning most of the twentieth century, the Morris Lapidus Papers comprise biographical material, correspondence, architectural work, writings and memorabilia of the Russian-born American architect, as well as a limited number of presentation drawings for several of his major projects. Documenting the development of Lapidus' philosophy of the "architecture of joy", the collection illuminates the career of this designer of retail stores, hotels and apartments.
Personal papers consists of a large number of family photographs and memorabilia, along with correspondence between Lapidus and his childhood friend, Manfred Lee (one half of the mystery-writing duo known as Ellery Queen), lists of books and records owned by Lapidus and some biographical publications/resumes.
Professional papers includes information on awards and honors that Lapidus received, exhibitions of his work, and photographs of most of his projects. This series also contains a very limited number of drawings for projects such as the Eden Roc, Americana and Fontainebleau Hotels. Correspondence mostly dates to later in Lapidus's career and relates to organizing lectures of his work. Much of the preparatory material for those lectures can also be found here.
Writings contains articles, books and essays (both fiction and architecture-related) written by Morris Lapidus. It also contains numerous newspaper and magazine articles about Lapidus and his work, in addition to a couple of thesis papers on Lapidus.
The final series is devoted to Deborah Desilets, a Florida architect and fashion designer who worked with Lapidus beginning in 1994. It is often difficult to distinguish between the output of Desilets and Lapidus during this time, especially as she often helped him to arrange and prepare lectures and developed his preliminary designs into more finished products. This series contains only material for which her authorship was clear, or which relates to projects wherein she was not working on Lapidus's behalf.
Audiovisual items have been assigned unique ID numbers (lapidus_01, lapidus_02 and so on). Please reference these numbers when requesting these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Lapidus, Morris.; Desilets, Deborah.; Queen, Ellery.; Ibelings, Hans.; Lee, Manfred B. (Manfred Bennington), 1905-1971.; Pelli, Cesar.; Risom, Jens.; Sanders, Joel.; Spear, Laurinda.; Tisch, Preston.; Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012.; Morris Lapidus Associates.; Morris Lapidus, Harle & Liebman.; Architectural League of New York.; Columbia University.; Cooper-Hewitt Museum.; Florida International University.; Smithsonian Institution.; Architects -- United States.; Architectural design.; Architectural drawing -- United States -- 20th century.; Architectural firms.; Architectural practice.; Architecture -- Designs and plans.; Architecture -- United States -- 20th century.; Architecture -- Human factors.; Architecture -- Psychological aspects.; Architecture -- Vocational guidance.; Architecture, American.; Architect-designed furniture.; Furniture designers.; Hotels -- Designs and plans.; Russian Americans.; Stores, Retail -- Designs and plans.; Painting -- United States -- 20th century.; Architectural drawings (visual works); Articles.; Audiocassettes.; Sound recordings.; CD-ROMs.; Correspondence.; DVDs.; Essays.; Exhibition catalogs.; Interviews.; Lectures.; Photographs.; Scripts (documents); Slides (photographs); Speeches (documents); VHS.; Architects.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to computer media or recordings requires advance notice.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Morris Lapidus, 1970-1988.
Additional materials gift of Deborah Desilets, 2011.
Inventory
- Personal papers
  - Biographical material
    - Biographical publications, 1961-1994 (Box 1)
    - List of library books (Box 1)
    - List of musical records (Box 1)
    - Mailing list, 1974; ML/BL copy (Box 1)
    - Resumes, 1955-1974; undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Lee, Manfred B. (aka Ellery Queen), 1956-1961 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-2005; undated (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia
    - Artifacts, art materials, mugs, sculpture, etc. (Oversize 9)
    - Artifacts, art materials, hard hat, vase, etc. (Oversize 10)
    - Biographical memorabilia, 1922-1927; 2001,; undated (Box 1)
    - Book plates (Box 1)
    - Books, includes Ellery Queen novel (signed), Vitruvius's Ten Books on Architecture and Ayn Rand's The Fountainhead (Oversize 9)
    - Holiday cards, 1971-1973; 2001 (Box 1)
    - Holiday cards, 1971-1973; oversize (Oversize 3)
    - Hotel memorabilia (Box 1)
    - Hotel memorabilia, oversize (Oversize 3)
    - Hotel guestbooks (Oversize 9)
    - Passports and driver's license, Beatrice Lapidus, 1960-1987 (Box 2)
    - Passports, Morris Lapidus, 1949-1999 (Box 2)
    - Photographs
      - Album, 1955 trip to Europe (Box 2)
      - Album, celebrities (Box 2)
      - Album, childhood and family (Box 2)
      - Album, Aura and miscellaneous portraits, circa 1995 (Box 2)
      - Family, 4 folders (Box 2)
      - House contents (Box 3)
      - Morris Lapidus (Box 3)
      - Photographs, oversize, mostly family photographs, includes one album of photographs with clients, architectural models, etc.; 5 folders (Oversize 3)
      - Paintings (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous photocopies of photographs (Box 3)
    - Slides, trip to China (Box 3)
    - Travel memorabilia (Box 3)
    - Travel videos
      - Europe Mr. Lapidus, lapidus_01; Home video of Morris and Beatrice Lapidus’s trip to Europe Liberty FF. Paris-France-Switzerland-Italy-Venice-Rome-Austria-Findland-Sweden-Norway-More!; VHS (Box 28)
      - Morris & Bea Travels (?), lapidus_02; Video from travels to Taipei, Phillippines, Singapore, Penang, Bangkok, Angkor Wat, Hong Kong, Salzburg, Bad Gastein, Oberammergau, Munich, Macoa, Hawaii; VHS (Box 28)
      - Morris and Bea Europe Trip, lapidus_17; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_01); DVD (Oversize 10)
      - Morris and Bea, Taipei, Malaysia, Hawaii Trip, lapidus_18; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_02); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Writing supplies (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Artwork, matted, artist unclear; some are photocopies; 4 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Audiovisual materials
        Audiovisual items have been assigned unique ID numbers (lapidus_01, lapidus_02 and so on). Please reference these numbers when requesting these items.
        - A.S. Beck Beginning, lapidus_44; Cass 1 Side 1; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_45; Cass 1 Side 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_46; Cass 2 Side 1; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_47; Cass 2 Side 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_48; Cass 3 Side 1; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_49; Cass 3, Side 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_50; Cass 4, Side 1; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_51; Cass 4, Side 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_52; Cass 5, Sides 1 and 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_53; Cass 6, Side 1; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_54; Cass 6, Side 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_55; Cass 7, Side 1; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_56; Cass 7, Side 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_57; Cass 8, Side 1 (or A); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_58; Cass 8, Side 2 (or B); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_59; Cass 9, Sides 1 and 2; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_60; Cass 10, Side 1 (or A); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_61; Cass 10, Side 1 (or A); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_62; Cass 10, Side 2 (or B); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_63; Cass 11, Sides 1 and 2 (or A and B); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_64; Cass 12, Side 1 (or A); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_65; Cass 12, Side 2 (or B); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_66; Cass 13, Side 1 (or A); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled - A.S. Beck?], lapidus_67; Cass 13, Side 2 (or B); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Eiber, lapidus_34; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Florida Moving Image Archive, lapidus_35; MiMo Bus Tour WC11143; Boxing TVS0361; Glamour WC08329; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Florida Moving Images Archive # WCO64SO; Miami Mendini, 03/15/1999; lapidus_28; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Morris Lapidus Master, lapidus_16; 8 mm Hi8 Video (Oversize 10)
        - Morris Lapidus Washington Deborah - L.R., lapidus_40; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Miami Mendini, 03/15/1999; lapidus_09; VHS; running time 23 min (Box 28)
        - Sunrise Assisted Living, Intro into the Victorian Sunrise, lapidus_42; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_14); DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Travels with Harry - Show #12, lapidus_14; VHS (Box 28)
        - Travels with Harry #12, lapidus_43; DVD, digitized version of lapidus_14 VHS tape; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - Various programs, lapidus_36; Miami Ad School-Student Reel; FL Moving Image WC11156; Miami Miami, Schöne; Sitten in Sobe, Claus Kleber; DVD (Oversize 10)
        - [Untitled], lapidus_15; VHS (Box 28)
      - Papers, includes symposium announcements, Spanish language exercises, etc.; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Papers, includes lecture announcement and journal cover; matted; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
- Professional papers
  - Awards and honors
    - American Institute of Architects, 1944; membership certificate (Oversize 3)
    - American Institute of Architects, Miami Chapter, 2000; Hall of Fame for Design (Oversize 3)
    - American Jewish Literary Foundation, 1960; citation (Oversize 3)
    - Columbia University, 1927; bachelor of architecture degree (Oversize 3)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum, 2000; National Design Award (Box 4)
    - Florida International University, 1998; honorary degree (Box 4)
    - Legion of Honor, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Library of Congress, 1973; certificate of honor (Box 4)
    - National Council of Architectural Registration Boards, 1945; license (Box 4)
    - New School of Architecture, certificate of appreciation (Box 4)
    - State of Florida, 1946; certification (Oversize 3)
    - State of Florida, 1997; commendation (Box 1)
    - State of New York, 1930; certification (Oversize 3)
    - Temple Emanu-El, 1964; certificate (Oversize 3)
    - Test of Time award, 1987; entry materials (Box 4)
    - A tribute to Morris Lapidus / Gateway dedication, 1999-2005 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence
    - Inventory of correspondence, includes personal and professional correspondence (Box 4)
    - American Institute of Architects, Florida, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Architectural League of New York, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Berens, Carol, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Blair, Gwenda, 1990-1998 (Box 4)
    - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Columbia University, 1986-2000; undated (Box 4)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Design and Architecture Senior High School, Miami, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Florida International University, 1997-2001 (Box 4)
    - Georgia Institute of Technology, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Harvard University, Graduate School of Design, 1996-2000 (Box 4)
    - Ibelings, Hans, 1991-1997 (Box 4)
    - Jewish Museum of Florida (Box 4)
    - Kalemeris, James, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Louisiana Tech University, 1997-2001 (Box 4)
    - Miodrag, Mitrasinovic, 1996 (Box 5)
    - National Building Museum, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Ohio State University, Austin E. Knowlton School of Architecture, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Pelli, Cesar, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Risom, Jens, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
    - Rizzoli International Publications, 1995-1996 (Box 5)
    - Roots Toronto, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Sanders, Joel, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Smithsonian Institution, 2000; undated (Box 5)
    - Soeters, Sjoerd, 1992-1995 (Box 5)
    - Spear, Laurinda, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    - Stuart, John, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
    - Syracuse University, 1966-1996 (Box 5)
    - Tisch, Preston, 2000 (Box 5)
    - University of Texas at Austin, School of Architecture, 1997-2002 (Box 5)
    - Wood & Zapata, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1966 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-1989 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1995 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
    - Letters/scan of letters, lapidus_68; CD (Box 4)
  - Exhibitions
    - 40 Years of Art and Architecture: Morris Lapidus (University of Miami, Joe & Emily Lowe Art Gallery), 1967 (Box 6)
    - 40 Years of Art and Architecture: Morris Lapidus (University of Miami, Joe & Emily Lowe Art Gallery), 1967; exhibition handouts (Oversize 3)
    - An Architecture of Joy (The Architectural League of New York), 1970 (Box 6)
    - An Architecture of Joy (The Architectural League of New York), 1970; exhibition handout, original newsprints version and photocopy (Oversize 3)
    - Forum Design (Hochschule für künsterlische und industrielle Gestaltung in Linz), 1980 (Box 6)
    - Happiness and delight: De architectuur van Morris Lapidus (Nederlands Architectuurinstituut), 1992 (Box 6)
    - Morris Lapidus: Mid-Century Modernist (California State University in Long Beach, University Art Museum), 1997 (Box 6)
    - Morris Lapidus: Mid-Century Modernist (California State University in Long Beach, University Art Museum), 1997; framed exhibition announcements (Oversize 3)
    - Morris Lapidus Paintings (Lowe Levinson Gallery) (Box 6)
    - A Quest for Emotion + Motion in Architecture (Art Center South Florida), 2010 (Box 6)
  - Interviews
    - Mike Wallace, 1961; transcript from the television program P.M. East (Box 6)
    - House of Style #27, Paris Edition, 1993; lapidus_03; VHS (Box 28)
    - House of Style #27, Paris Edition 1993 (1), lapidus_19; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_03); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - House of Style #27, Paris Edition 1993 (2), lapidus_20; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_03); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Abramovitz, Ingrid (House & Garden), April 29, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Live Wire TV, “Morris Lapidus”, 07/22/1998; lapidus_08; VHS (Box 28)
    - Live Wire TV #30, 07/22/1998; lapidus_26; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_08); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Morris Lapidus [interview], 11/18/1998; lapidus_27; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - M. L. CNN Report, 07/11/2000; lapidus_29; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Charlie Rose: Morris Lapidus, 11/23/2000; lapidus_10; interview with Morris Lapidus; VHS (Box 28)
    - Charlie Rose Interview, 11/23/2000; lapidus_30; interview with Morris Lapidus; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_10); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Morris Lapidus with Mark Hurt, 02/04/2001; lapidus_11; VHS (Box 28)
    - Morris Lapidus Mark Hurt, 02/04/2001; lapidus_31; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Cohen, Gary article on Meyer Lansky for which Morris was interviewed (Box 6)
    - Morris Lapidus Join us at the Bass, Parts 5, 6, 7, 8, lapidus_37; program at the Bass Museum of Art; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_12); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Klotz & Cook (Box 6)
    - Join Us at the Bass, Part 5, 6, 7, 8, lapidus_12; program at the Bass Museum of Art; VHS (Box 28)
    - CBS Sunday, Morris Lapidus Passage, lapidus_32; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - CBS Sunday, Morris Lapidus Passage, lapidus_33; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Open to the Public Show 48, lapidus_39; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Pride of Place, lapidus_13; Robert A. M. Stern interviews Morris Lapidus; VHS (Box 28)
    - Price of Place, Robert Stern, lapidus_41; Robert A. M. Stern interviews Morris Lapidus; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_13); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified interview, partial transcript of taped conversation (Box 6)
  - Lectures
    - Allmann Award acceptance speech, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Ancient Civilizations (Box 6)
    - Ancient Civilizations (Box 7)
    - Announcements, 1992-1997; undated (Box 7)
    - "The Architects of Miami Beach", [1998]; signed poster (Oversize 4)
    - "Beyond Walls" (Massachusetts Institute of Technology / San Diego) (Box 7)
    - "The Dynamics of Restaurant Design", 1959 (Box 7)
    - "The Edges of Architecture", 1997 (Box 7)
    - "Fifty Years as an Architect" (Winterend Lecture, University of Washington), 1980; includes slides (Box 7)
    - GDCI luncheon lecture, 1961 (Box 7)
    - "Hotel Design & Merchandising" (Seminar at Cornell University, School of Hotel Administration) (Box 7)
    - Lincoln Road for AIA Welcome from Morris Lapidus Archive, 02/26/2010; lapidus_71; CD (Box 12)
    - "Morris Lapidus", 1997; poster (Oversize 4)
    - Morris Lapidus Day, Dash Media Center, 04/16/1998; lapidus_07; VHS (Box 28)
    - Morris Lapidus Day, Dash Media Center, 04/16/1998; lapidus_25; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_07); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - "Morris Lapidus in Miami Beach", program (Oversize 4)
    - "Off Color," Al Eiber House, Jul 1997; lapidus_23; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - "Off Color," Al Eiber House, Jul 1997; lapidus_24; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - "Pressing Style", 1997; posters (Oversize 4)
    - Young Architects' Forum keynote address, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Morris Lapidus Lecture, FAMU SOA Spring Lecture Series, March 24, 1997; lapidus_06; Morris Lapidus Lecture given at the Florida A & M University School of Architecture; VHS (Box 28)
    - FAMU SOA Spring Lecture Series, March 24, 1997; lapidus_22; Morris Lapidus Lecture given at the Florida A & M University School of Architecture; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_06); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Harvard 1994 Short Clips Lecture, lapidus_04; VHS (Box 28)
    - Harvard Lecture, VTM, Morris Lapidus, 1994; lapidus_05; VHS (Box 28)
    - Morris Lapidus Lecture Harvard, 1994; lapidus_21; 1994 lecture given by Morris Lapidus at Harvard University; possibly a digital version of a VHS tape (lapidus_05); DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Morris Lapidus Lecture, lapidus_38; DVD (Oversize 10)
    - Miscellaneous lecture notes (Box 7)
  - Office records
    - Deed of gift to Bass Museum of Art, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Lecture arrangements, 1997-1999; undated (Box 7)
    - Letterhead (Box 7)
    - Memorable quotes, about or by Lapidus (Box 7)
    - Office brochures, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Office brochures mock-ups (Box 8)
    - Press releases, 1950-1995; undated (Box 8)
    - Staff, list of office alumni (Box 8)
  - Projects
    - Lists of work, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - 17 Battery Place, office building (New York, New York), black and white photograph (Box 8)
    - 18th Street building (Washington, DC), 1966; black and white photograph (Box 8)
    - 555 Madison Avenue (New York, New York), 1957; black and white photograph (Box 8)
    - Ainsley building (Miami, Florida), 1951; undated; black and white photographs (Box 8)
    - Aldine Paper Company, black and white photograph (Box 8)
    - Alix of Miami (Miami, Florida), black and white photograph (Box 8)
    - Algiers Hotel (Miami Beach, Florida), photocopy (Box 8)
    - Americana Hotel (Bar Harbour, Florida)
      - Drawings, includes floor and site plans (one has a color photograph of the model attached) (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white and color (Box 8)